{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The process by which phage reproduction is initiated in lysogenized culture is called", "opta": "infection", "optb": "integration", "optc": "repression", "optd": "induction", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Area of lysis on a bacterial lawn culture produced by a phage is known as", "opta": "pock", "optb": "plaque", "optc": "pox", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The procapsid is assembled with the aid of __________ proteins.", "opta": "ladder", "optb": "framing", "optc": "scaffolding", "optd": "form", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is/are synthesized from late mRNA?", "opta": "Phage structural proteins", "optb": "Proteins that help with phage assembly without becoming part of the virion structure", "optc": "Proteins involved in cell lysis and phage release", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which capsid symmetry is exhibited by most of the phages?", "opta": "Helical", "optb": "Icosahedral", "optc": "Complex", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Contractile sheath of the tail is present in which of the following phages?", "opta": "T3", "optb": "T2", "optc": "P22", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of the first enzymes synthesized by many bacteriophage is __________ , an RNA-dependent RNA polymerase.", "opta": "RNA transcriptase", "optb": "RNA polymerase", "optc": "RNA ligase", "optd": "RNA replicase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In viruses with envelopes", "opta": "the envelope and the embedded proteins are encoded by the viral nucleic acid", "optb": "the envelope is derived from the host but it contains embedded proteins coded by the viral nucleic acid", "optc": "the envelope is coded by the viral nucleic acids, but the proteins come from the host's membrane proteins", "optd": "the envelope and its imbedded proteins are derived from the host's membranes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacteria can be typed by phage typing method?", "opta": "Staphylococcus aureus", "optb": "Salmonella typhi", "optc": "Vibrio cholerae", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ protein keeps the prophage dormant and prevents virus reproduction.", "opta": "Operator", "optb": "Promotor", "optc": "Repressor", "optd": "Enhancer", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "__________ is specifically able to have a long-term relationship with the host known as lysogeny.", "opta": "Temperate virus", "optb": "Adsorbed virus", "optc": "RNA phage", "optd": "DNA phage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following properties is due to lysogenic conversion by phages?", "opta": "Toxin production in Corynebacterium diphtheriae", "optb": "Toxin production in Clostridium botulinum types C and D", "optc": "Antigenic variation in Salmonella anatum", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "T-even phage binding to E. coli probably involves", "opta": "electrostatic interaction", "optb": "hydrophobic interaction", "optc": "covalent bonds", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The filamentous bacteriopohage infect male E. coli cells by attaching to", "opta": "lipopolysaccharide", "optb": "the cell wall", "optc": "the tip of the pilus", "optd": "the cell membrane", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A bacterial defense mechanism against bacteriophage is called", "opta": "concatamerization", "optb": "polymerization", "optc": "restriction", "optd": "lysogeny", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}